billofrightsinstitute.org 2015-11-20

# Privacy Policy - Bill of Rights Institute

The Bill of Rights Institute (Institute) respects individuals’ concerns about the privacy of their information. This Privacy Policy applies to personal information the Institute collects both online and offline. The Policy describes the types of personal information we may collect, how we may use that personal information and with whom we may share it, as well as the measures we take to help protect the security of the personal information. We also tell you how you can contact us to update or remove your personal information or receive answers to questions you may have about our privacy practices. Please note that this policy applies only to sites maintained by the Institute, and not to websites maintained by other organizations to which we may link.

By registering for an online Institute Account, using this site and/or any of the Institute’s online or mobile products and services (such as DocsofFreedom.org), and/or attend an in-person program you agree to the Institute’s Privacy Policy. By registering, you agree that the Institute may process your data in accordance with the following privacy policy and that you will abide by the Institute’s Terms and Conditions.

IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT USE ANY INSTITUTE SITE, ONLINE OR MOBILE PRODUCT OR SERVICE OR PROGRAMS. If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page or other places so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. Your continued use of our online and mobile products and services will signify your acceptance of the changes to our online Privacy Policy.

### **Personal Information We May Collect About You**

We may collect personal information, such as name, email and postal address, telephone number, academic information, and financial information from customers, job applicants, employees, contractors, vendors, and other individuals through our websites or by other means, such as email, fax, postal mail, mobile applications, or telephone. In addition, prize winners may be required to provide their Social Security or other identification number for tax purposes.

The Institute may collect personal information from our visitors during:

>   * Registration for programs, games, and/or specific events;
>   * Creation of a personal profile;
>   * Newsletter subscriptions, referral services, and other marketing surveys and email campaigns;
>   * Product, service and/or subscription orders; Contest registration and prize acceptance;
>   * Access to our products and/or services on social networks or other third party services; and
>   * Otherwise through use of our software, mobile or online services where personal information is required for use and/or participation.
> 

Please note that some third party services, such as Twitter and Facebook, may also provide us with information from your accounts with your permission.

The Institute does not wish to receive any personally identifiable information pertaining to any individual unless all requisite permissions have been obtained in advance, including parental consent.  You hereby represent and warrant to the Institute that you have full authority to submit the personally identifiable information and other information required for any interaction with the site.

### **How the Institute Uses Your Information**

The Institute uses your information to fulfill your specific requests, purchase orders and to send you purchase confirmation and other account-related information. In addition, the personal information you provide will allow us to send you messages about things including new products, features, enhancements, special offers, contests, other related programs, and events of interest. You, or in the case of children aged 17 and below, your parents, may also later opt out of any or all of these communications.

The Institute may also use personal information to better understand the behavior and preferences of our customers, to troubleshoot technical problems, to enforce our Terms and Conditions, to ensure proper functioning of our products and services as well as to help improve them. In addition, we combine non-personal information with personal information, such as an email address, to administer loyalty programs, tailor our offerings, and web experience to you.  Your information may be shared with or transferred to our affiliates and any other organization or entity for similar purposes.

Furthermore, we may share the information with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf. These service providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process; (ii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials; or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity.

### **Public Information Including User Generated Content, Online Forums, Blogs and Profiles**

You may choose to disclose information about yourself in the course of contributing user generated content to Institute sites or games or in our online chat rooms, blogs, message boards, user “profiles” for public view or in similar forums on our sites and/or on third party sites. Information that you disclose in any of these forums is public information, and there is no expectation of privacy or confidentiality there.

You should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit in the course of these public activities can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information (or any other information) you choose to make public in any of these forums.

Note also that in the ordinary course of Internet activity, certain information may be sent from your browser to third parties such as advertising networks and analytics companies. The Institute has no control over the information sent from your browser to those networks or other third parties and recommends that you ensure that your browser settings prevent the disclosure of information you would not like to share.

### **How We Protect Personal Information**

We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and/or physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction of the information you provide.

You should be aware that “perfect security” does not exist on the internet or on mobile communications equipment.  As a consequence, there is always a risk that unauthorized persons may use or access your personally identifiable information.  You use our website and other technologies to send us information at your own risk.  If you are worried because your communication is sensitive, do not send it electronically.

### **Special Note on Donors**

The Institute is committed to protecting the privacy of our donors. We honor your privacy and respect your choice not to have your personal information shared with other organizations. Occasionally the Institute exchanges names with other like-minded non-profit organizations for purposes of its direct mail campaign. The direct mail exchange process is an essential element of our program, enabling us to reach more supporters while keeping expenses as low as possible. Any other use of these names is prohibited. These names cannot be rented, sold, or exchanged and data on these files cannot be used to enhance other data files without written permission from the Institute.

From time to time, we will invite our donors to observe our programs and they may wish to send a supporting message to the students. We do not allow direct communications contact between donors and students except with the express approval from the students’ parents. The Institute staff will serve as the main point of contact for sending such communications.

### **Special Note on Students**

We are concerned about the safety and privacy of children who use the internet and who participate in our programs.  Our website is not designed for or directed to children under the age of 13. No information should be submitted nor posted to Institute online sites by students 13 years of age or under without express parental consent. In certain jurisdictions, notification, prior written permission or other verifiable consent may be required of a parent or guardian for children from 13 to 17 years of age. If you believe your child has provided us with information without your consent, please email us at address set forth in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

From time to time, we will have donors observe our programs and they may wish to send a supporting message to the students. We do not allow direct communications contact between donors and students except with the express approval from the students’ parents. The Institute staff will serve as the main point of contact for such communications.

Since an email address is necessary to respond to lost password requests and account administration, in some circumstances we may ask for a student’s email address. Newsletter subscriptions are handled similarly.

Our Constitutional Quiz website permits students to create an account, upload a picture file to personalize an account, select their state, and identify their grade level. The student may also use the social media feature to share our website with others. This information gathered is not shared with anyone outside of the Institute. We will use the aggregate information to assess civic understanding in the US by state and by grade level.

Information collected is secured in a manner consistent with this privacy policy.

Parents have the right to consent prior to the collection of their children’s information.  All information collected will be treated by the Institute in accordance with this Privacy Policy and Terms & Conditions. Parents also have the right to restrict access to their children’s information.  Parents should be aware that exercising such right will restrict their children’s use of the Site. If for any reason you are concerned that your student’s personally identifiable information maintained by the Institute is not correct or complete, should you wish to have your child’s personal information deleted from our records, or if you want the Institute to discontinue further collection or use of your student’s personal information, please contact the Institute at [info@billofrightsinstitute.org](mailto:info@billofrightsinstitute.org).

### **Job Search Data**

You may be able to submit your resume and other information for a job with the Institute. The information you provide in connection with your job search is maintained with for the sole purpose of the job search. We use the information you submit to evaluate your qualifications for employment and to contact you regarding possible employment opportunities with the Institute.

### **Websites for Institute Access**

On our websites, you may be able to register to gain access to information and services that provide more benefits from the Institute. To register, we may ask you for details such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, user id and password. We use these details to provide you with secure access to information about your business relationship with us and to facilitate your use of the websites.

### **Vendors, Contractors and Customers**

If you are a vendor, contractor, or customer for the Institute, we may ask you to provide information such as your contact information, tax identification number, date of birth, driver’s license or other identification number, or financial information to establish and administer your account or process payments, and for compliance with internal and legal requirements.

### **Links to Other Sites**

Our websites and communications may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. Linked sites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. To the extent any linked websites you visit are not part of the Institute, we are not responsible for their content, any use of the sites, or the privacy practices of the sites.

### **Contact Us**

You may contact us with questions, feedback, requests or comments on our website or by other means, such as email, fax, postal mail, or telephone. When you do so, we may ask you for information such as your name, email address, and telephone number. We use the information to respond to your questions and comments. We also may use the information you provide to evaluate the quality of our products and to communicate with you about products and services.

### **How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy or you would like to correct or update your account information then please log on to our site and navigate to “My Account,” “View My Profile” or other account settings. Should you be unable to log in or wish to have your account(s) deactivated, contact the Institute at [info@billofrightsinstitute.org](mailto:info@billofrightsinstitute.org) or by mailing:

Bill of Rights Institute  
Attn: Operations  
200 N. Glebe Rd, Suite 200  
Arlington, VA 22203

## **Terms & Conditions**

The Bill of Rights Institute (Institute) is a not for profit organization whose mission is to educate young people about the Constitution. As we have a focus on continuous improvement, we will request information from and communicate with participants of our programs and products that will be utilized in analysis of our program effectiveness. We also expect consumers of our programs and products to adhere by the general terms and conditions.

These Terms & Conditions form a legally binding contract between you and the Institute. By using Institute programs and products, you affirm that you are at least 18 years of age (or have reached the age of majority if that is not 18 years of age where you live) or that you have reviewed this Agreement with your parent or guardian and he or she assents to these Terms & Conditions on your behalf and takes full responsibility for your compliance with them. You agree that you and/or your parent or guardian are fully able and competent to enter into the terms, conditions, obligations, representations and responsibilities set forth in these Terms & Conditions, and to abide and comply with these Terms & Conditions.

### **Program Participant Data & Measurement**

By participating in an Institute program for teachers and/or students, such as professional development seminars, online webinars, academy, and contests you agreed to provide:

>   * Personal Information: name, email, postal address, and telephone number
>   * Demographic Information: gender, age, grade, grades taught, and subjects taught
>   * Knowledge Gain: You agree to participate in knowledge assessment prior to a program, immediately after a program, and within three months of a program, such as topics from a program, awareness of Institute products, etc.
> 

### **Permission to Utilize Comments, Photos, Audio & Visual Recordings from Institute Programs**

By participating in an Institute program, you authorize the Institute to utilize the comments you provide, whether verbal, written, or recorded, photos & videos taken by Institute videographers, in Institute marketing materials, grant reports, and other Institute related requirements. The Institute has the right to, and allow others to: use, copy, and distribute all of your comments and any other content you submit to us without compensating or notifying you.

### **Reliability of Information with Online Accounts**

To create an Account, you must have an email address, and provide truthful and accurate information. You may not use a user name or persona that is used by someone else, is vulgar or offensive, or otherwise violates the Terms & Conditions.

You are solely responsible for all activity on your Account. Your Account may be terminated if someone else uses it to engage in activity that violates the Terms & Conditions or is otherwise improper or illegal. You should not reveal your Account password to others. The Institute will not ask you to reveal your password, or initiate contact with you asking for answers to your password security questions.

The Institute reserves the right (but has no obligation) to remove, block, edit, move or disable user generated content that is objectionable to us for any reason. The decision to remove user generated content or other Content at any time is in the Institute’s sole and final discretion.

### **Use Content and General License Restrictions**

The Institute grants you a personal, limited, non-exclusive license to use Content to which you have access for your personal, private, non-commercial, non-transferable, limited uses solely as set forth herein and as set forth in any additional documentation and/or agreements applicable to the Institute resources accessed by you. Content and all other intellectual property rights in or on Institute resources are owned by the Institute and are protected by United States and International copyright, trade dress, patent, and trademark laws, international conventions, and other laws protecting intellectual property and related proprietary rights. You may not copy or download any Content from an Institute site unless you are expressly authorized to do so. In addition, unless expressly authorized by the Institute, you may not distribute, publicly display, lease, sell, transmit, transfer, publish, edit, copy, create derivative works from, rent, sub-license, distribute or otherwise make unauthorized use of Content. You agree not to remove, obscure, or alter copyright, patent, trademark, or other proprietary rights notices affixed to Content. Your rights are subject to your compliance with these Terms & Conditions as well as any other agreements applicable to the Institute resources you are using.

The Institute reserves all right, title and interest in Content, and all associated copyrights, trademarks, and other intellectual property rights therein that are not expressly granted to you in these Terms and Conditions. Your permitted use of Content described above is limited by the intellectual property rights of the Institute and does not include any rights to other patents or intellectual property. Making unauthorized copies or distribution of Content found on Institute resources may result in the termination of your Account(s), prohibition on use of Institute resources, and further legal action.

### **Prohibited Uses of Our Site and Content**

The Institute has the right (but not the obligation) to monitor our website for any violations of the below policies and to take appropriate actions in response (including removing material submitted to our website), without notice to you. We reserve the right to change or supplement these policies at any time.

>   * You may not post or send through our website any materials or communications that are defamatory, obscene, profane, indecent, pornographic, harassing, threatening, abusive, or otherwise objectionable, as determined in the Institute’s sole discretion.
>   * You may not post or send through our website any materials or communications that may be deemed to be lobbying or electioneering communications within the meaning of applicable federal law.
>   * You may not (and may not encourage others to) violate any law, regulation, rule or the intellectual property, privacy or publicity, or contractual rights of others, or attempt to violate the security of our website or use or gain access to the identities, information or computers of others through our website.
>   * You may not use our website for commercial, marketing or advertising purposes or to solicit information, transactions or money from other users of our website.
>   * You may not use our website to engage in spamming, flooding, flaming, trolling, spoofing, phishing or other unauthorized or unwelcome online conduct.
>   * You may not transmit any virus, worm, time bomb or similar system interference through our website site.
> 

### **Indemnification**

Upon the Institute’s request, you agree to defend, indemnify and hold harmless the Institute, affiliates, contractors, vendors, and content providers from all liabilities, claims and expenses, including attorneys’ fees, that arise from or relate to a breach of these Terms and Conditions for which you are responsible or in connection with your distribution of any Content on or through Institute resources. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, you agree to indemnify and hold the Institute harmless for any improper or illegal use of your Account, including the illegal or improper use of your Account by someone to whom you have given permission to use your Account. You agree that you will be personally responsible for your use of Institute resources and for all of your communication and activity using Institute resources, including any Content you contribute, and that you will indemnify and hold harmless the Institute and its affiliates from any liability or damages arising from your conduct with Institute resources, including any Content that you contribute.

The Institute reserves the right, at its own expense, to assume the exclusive defense and control of any matter otherwise subject to indemnification by you. In that event, you shall have no further obligation to provide indemnification to the Institute in that matter. This Section shall survive termination of this Terms and Conditions.

### **General Terms  
**

A. Remedies. You agree that this Terms and Conditions is not intended to confer and does not confer any rights or remedies upon any person other than the parties to this Terms and Conditions. You also understand and agree that this Terms and Conditions, the Institute Privacy Policy are not intended to confer, and do not confer, any rights or remedies upon any person.

B. Severability. If any part of this Terms and Conditions is held invalid or unenforceable, that portion shall be interpreted in a manner consistent with applicable law to reflect, as nearly as possible, the original intentions of the Institute, and the remaining portions shall remain in full force and effect.

C. Waiver. The failure of the Institute to exercise or enforce any right or provision of this Terms and Conditions will not constitute waiver of such right or provision. Any waiver of any provision of this Terms and Conditions will be effective only if in a writing signed by the Institute.

D. Governing Law. The laws of the State of Virginia govern this Terms and Conditions and also are subject to other local, state, federal laws.

### **Entire Agreement**

The Terms and Conditions (including the Institute’s Privacy Policy) and any posted rules or instructions regarding a particular program, game, or contest, constitute the entire agreement between you and the Institute relating to your rights and obligations in the use of Institute resources. If there is any conflict between the Terms and Conditions and any other rules or instructions posted by the Institute, the Institute shall resolve the conflict in its sole discretion.
